Rodney Matambo Software Engineer

Profile

I'm a Full Stack Software Engineer who is passionate about solving problems. I have multiple years of experience programming. I have used languages like Ruby, JavaScript, GoLang, SQL, HTML and CSS, I have also worked extensively with aws and hold a Cloud Practitioner certification with AWS.

Experience

Co-Creater, Software Engineer, *Jolt*

2021 - present

Jolt is a lightweight open-source framework for deploying JAMstack applications(like netlify or vercel - static sites) with serverless functions(like netlify functions)

- Designed and lead the implementation of atomic deployments, rollbacks and teardown of AWS cloud app infrastructure using the SDK(IAM, API Gateway, Lambda, DynamoDB, CloudFront, S3)
- Implemented relative path redirection from CloudFront to API Gateway using edge computing (Lambda@Edge, CORS, HTTP).
- Contributed to creating a local testing environment for testing serverless functions with applications (Express, AWS Lambda).
- Implemented the mvp of Jolt using the AWS GoLang SDK(later switched to JS SDK)
- Worked with a remote team of engineers during sprints to make design decisions for Jolt(Agile Workflow).
- Authored Jolt's Technical Case-Study: https://core-jamstack.github.io/jolt-framework/

Software Engineer, *Self Employed*

2020 - 2021

- COREbin a realtime RequestBin clone for interacting with and debugging webhooks(Node, Socket.io(websockets), Nginx, Redis, Digital Ocean Droplet, PM2)
- Trollo A trello Clone(MongoDB, Express, Node, React-Redux, ReactDnD, Moment)
- Shopping Cart a simple Shopping Cart App(React-Redux, Graphql API, MongoDB, Node)
- Contacts: A contacts manager app(¡Query, Express, Node, PostgreSQL)
- JAMboard: an interactive whiteboard (Gatsby, Netlify Functions, FaunaDB, Node).

Freelance Wordpress Developer, Various

2014 - 2020

- Deployed Wordpress sites using AWS Lightsail, dealt with server crashes, database backups, digital certificate renewals and integrated stripe api to E-commerce sites.
- Created WordPress sites with different hosting providers for Non-profit groups that raised global awareness of communities.

Teacher/School Director, Various

2012 - 2020

- Taught in different contexts with diverse student and staff populations: African, Buddhist, Christian, Public, Private, Special Needs, Orphaned and underprivileged students.
- Directed a school for underprivileged students doing non-profit work and generated revenue for the school fees through student projects.

Skills(* indicates limited familiarity)

Languages

JavaScript, GoLang*, Ruby, SQL, HTML, CSS

Cloud

AWS: SDK, IAM, EC2, EBS, Lambda, Cloudwatch, Cloudtrail, LightSail, S3, CloudFront, DynamoDB, API Gateway, VPC, EFS, Amplify*, CloudFormation* Other: Digital Ocean Droplets, Heroku

Frameworks

React/Redux, Sinatra, HandlebarsJS, jQuery, Express

Technologies

Github Actions, HTTP, WebSockets, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, REST APIs, GraphQL, concurrency*, Nginx, Redis, faunaDB

Education

Software Engineering, Launch School

2020 - 2021

B.A Educational Studies(Chemistry Education),

Western Governors University

2016 - 2019

Cisco Certified Network Associate program, Tulsa Technology Center

2009 – 2010

3rd place in the state for proficiency with networking, network protocols, TCP/IP, subnets, routing protocols, and practical programming of switches and routers